<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sandcastles Archive</title><link>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/</link><description>Recent content on Sandcastles Archive</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>You are letting animals die by missing out on AI productivity</title><link>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2026-02-20-animal-advocacy-orgs-ai-agents/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2026-02-20-animal-advocacy-orgs-ai-agents/</guid><description>&lt;p>This essay argues that animal advocacy organizations must immediately adopt AI agents like OpenClaw and Claude Cowork to dramatically increase their operational capacity. The author contends that failing to leverage these tools results in preventable animal suffering.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ai-capabilities-have-arrived">AI Capabilities Have Arrived&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The author traces AI development through several milestones—Deep Research, Claude Code, and OpenClaw—demonstrating that autonomous AI agents can now perform complex digital work independently. OpenClaw specifically enables persistent agents that can manage emails, calendars, research, coding, and administrative tasks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Preparing the Animal Movement for AGI</title><link>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2026-01-29-input-needed-ai-animal-advocacy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2026-01-29-input-needed-ai-animal-advocacy/</guid><description>&lt;p>This piece argues that the animal advocacy movement&amp;rsquo;s strategic assumptions have become outdated due to imminent artificial general intelligence (AGI) development. The author identifies three major shifts that will reshape advocacy:&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="funding-transformation">Funding Transformation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The author contends that animal advocacy may soon transition from being funding-constrained (~$300 million annually) to capital-abundant. Anticipated IPOs of frontier AI companies like Anthropic could redirect substantial philanthropic resources toward animal welfare causes, creating what the author calls &amp;ldquo;the largest transfer of wealth to rigorously altruistic people in human history.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My New Year's Resolution: Hear No Gossip</title><link>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2026-01-23-hear-no-gossip-activists/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2026-01-23-hear-no-gossip-activists/</guid><description>&lt;p>This comprehensive essay examines how gossip undermines activist communities and proposes strategies to reduce its harmful effects. The author argues that gossip functions as a demand-side problem—people spread rumors because others eagerly consume them—rather than a supply-side issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-psychology-of-belief">The Psychology of Belief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Research demonstrates that humans automatically believe statements upon understanding them. As the author notes, &amp;ldquo;the first story we hear anchors a narrative in our mind that&amp;rsquo;s hard to revise.&amp;rdquo; Even when corrections arrive later, initial impressions persist and distort subsequent judgments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vegans Are Monks. We Need a Role for Laypeople.</title><link>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2026-01-09-vegans-are-monks-offsets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2026-01-09-vegans-are-monks-offsets/</guid><description>&lt;p>The article proposes that the animal advocacy movement should adopt a two-tiered structure modeled after religious institutions, where vegans function as a &amp;ldquo;priestly class&amp;rdquo; while non-vegans participate as supporters through donations and other low-commitment actions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-veganism-plateau-problem">The Veganism Plateau Problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The author notes that despite three decades of vegan advocacy, veganism has stagnated at 1-4% globally. Meanwhile, meat consumption continues rising. This suggests that &amp;ldquo;individual veganism appears to offer only limited potential&amp;rdquo; for achieving animal liberation at scale.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Constructive Infighting</title><link>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2026-01-06-constructive-infighting-forget-veganuary/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2026-01-06-constructive-infighting-forget-veganuary/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article examines two strategic disagreements within the animal advocacy movement that exemplified productive conflict: Farmkind&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Forget Veganuary&amp;rdquo; campaign and Animal Rising&amp;rsquo;s challenge to the RSPCA&amp;rsquo;s welfare certification scheme.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="case-1-farmkinds-offsetting-strategy">Case 1: Farmkind&amp;rsquo;s Offsetting Strategy&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In late December 2025, former Veganuary advocate Toni Vernilli launched a campaign suggesting meat-eaters could offset their consumption through donations rather than dietary change. The forgetveganuary.com site featured a calculator determining monthly giving amounts to effective animal charities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Three Soul-Meltingly Hot Takes for Animal Activists in 2026</title><link>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2026-01-01-animal-activist-hot-takes-2026/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2026-01-01-animal-activist-hot-takes-2026/</guid><description>&lt;p>The author acknowledges feedback from readers who find lengthy weekly posts challenging. This piece offers a shorter format with intentionally provocative predictions for 2026, framed as &amp;ldquo;hot takes&amp;rdquo; for the animal advocacy movement.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hot-take-1-ai-acceleration">Hot Take #1: AI Acceleration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The author predicts continued exponential progress in artificial intelligence throughout 2026, despite skeptics claiming the field has plateaued. Specific predictions include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The METR task-length chart will demonstrate a 4-5 month doubling time or faster for capability improvements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Visible impacts on U.S. employment, particularly in white-collar sectors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No significant market correction despite increasing economic dependence on AI investments&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="hot-take-2-cancel-culture-obsolescence">Hot Take #2: Cancel Culture Obsolescence&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The author argues that social ostracism as a corrective mechanism has become ineffective. The prediction asserts that attempted cancellations will fail because society has collectively rejected this approach. The author advocates reconnecting with previously ostracized individuals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The End of Animal Advocacy</title><link>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2025-12-26-ai-end-animal-advocacy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2025-12-26-ai-end-animal-advocacy/</guid><description>&lt;p>The author argues that transformative AI development presents an unprecedented but rapidly closing window of opportunity for animal advocates. He estimates 5-10 years remain before AI fundamentally reshapes society, leaving activists with roughly 260 weeks to act strategically.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="core-argument">Core Argument&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The author contends that &amp;ldquo;what may turn out to be the greatest window of opportunity for animal advocacy in human history is starting to close.&amp;rdquo; Unlike previous social movements, animal advocates now face concrete timelines measured in years rather than decades, forcing a complete reassessment of movement strategy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Governments Should Pay People Who Stop Mass Shootings</title><link>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2025-12-19-pay-mass-shooting-heroes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2025-12-19-pay-mass-shooting-heroes/</guid><description>&lt;p>The article proposes that governments should financially reward civilians who successfully stop mass shootings. The author uses the December 2025 Bondi Beach shooting in Australia as a case study, where an unarmed bystander named Ahmed al-Ahmed tackled one of the gunmen, potentially preventing additional deaths.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-monetary-value-framework">The Monetary Value Framework&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Governments already assign dollar values to human lives for policy decisions. Australia values a statistical life at 5.7 million AUD, while U.S. agencies range from 7.5 to 13+ million USD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Your Activism Is Ego-Driven (And That's Fine)</title><link>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2025-12-16-ego-is-ok-animal-activism/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2025-12-16-ego-is-ok-animal-activism/</guid><description>&lt;p>This essay explores the tension between personal ego and effective animal activism. The author argues that while individual activists&amp;rsquo; needs aren&amp;rsquo;t perfectly aligned with maximum impact for animals, understanding and channeling ego can actually strengthen movements.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-unavoidable-ego">The Unavoidable Ego&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The author contends that completely setting aside ego is impossible. Instead, activists should recognize their psychological drives—ambition, desire for recognition, intellectual challenge—and learn to align them with movement goals. As he explains, &amp;ldquo;your personal needs are, by default, not perfectly aligned to the goal of creating as much change for animals as possible.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How 17th-Century Theology Hijacked an Animal Rights Debate</title><link>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2025-12-10-roots-of-welfarist-abolitionist-animal-rights/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2025-12-10-roots-of-welfarist-abolitionist-animal-rights/</guid><description>&lt;p>This essay traces the philosophical roots of the abolitionist versus welfarist divide in animal advocacy back to John Milton&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Paradise Lost&lt;/em> and Protestant theology. The author argues that the prioritization of freedom over welfare—central to abolitionist opposition to cage-free campaigns—originates from Milton&amp;rsquo;s theological solution to the problem of evil, which then influenced liberal political philosophy through thinkers like John Locke.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-theological-foundation">The Theological Foundation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Milton&amp;rsquo;s God permits human suffering because freedom is more valuable than safety. As the author explains, God justifies creating humans destined for damnation by asserting: &amp;ldquo;I made him just and right, Sufficient to have stood, though free to fall.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>When Activists Start Thinking Like Bureaucrats</title><link>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2025-12-04-activists-thinking-like-bureaucrats/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2025-12-04-activists-thinking-like-bureaucrats/</guid><description>&lt;p>This essay argues that progressive activists have developed an authoritarian streak that manifests through excessive rulemaking at both governmental and interpersonal levels. The author traces this tendency from formal regulations (like NEPA environmental rules) to informal social policing within activist communities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-arguments">Key Arguments&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Core Problem:&lt;/strong> Inside every activist are two competing forces—the &amp;ldquo;rigid radical&amp;rdquo; who obsesses over perfection and the &amp;ldquo;joyful militant&amp;rdquo; who finds meaning in imperfect progress. When rigid radicalism dominates, it creates self-defeating regulations and toxic community dynamics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Radical Welfarists vs. the Moderate Abolitionists</title><link>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2025-11-28-radical-welfarist-moderate-abolitionist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sandcastles.kankyoku.com/posts/2025-11-28-radical-welfarist-moderate-abolitionist/</guid><description>&lt;p>This essay challenges conventional animal advocacy terminology by arguing that welfare campaigns for farmed animals represent more radical activism than traditional abolitionist approaches. The author contends that public indifference to farmed animals makes even modest welfare improvements narratively powerful, while campaigns for companion animals fail to shift attitudes toward factory farming.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-arguments">Key Arguments&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Categorization Problem&lt;/strong>
The author demonstrates that most people sort animals into fixed mental categories—pets, wild animals, vermin, and farmed animals—based on their relationship to humans rather than inherent moral worth. These categories don&amp;rsquo;t easily transfer; campaigning against greyhound racing won&amp;rsquo;t increase concern for chickens.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>